The seige of Gaza, cutting off all supplies of fuel
the electricity plant, that's gone
there's no electricity, there's no running
water
there's no food going in, there are no other
fuel supplies going in
the border's closed at Egypt as well
there's highly little criticism of Egypt at
that, interestingly
Is that, and while raining down missiles on
buildings
which they know are going to kill civilians
we know hundreds and hundreds of civilians
already died
many of them children -
is that a reasonable, proportionate and moral
response
by Israel?
There's some deep perversion in Britain, whenever
Israel is involved in a conflict
and it is the word you just used: proportion
proportionate, proportionality
Only Britain is really obsessed with this
I've heard it the last few days insessidly
proportionality in conflict
rarely exists
but if we were to decide that we should have
this fetish
about proportionality
then that would mean that in retaliation for
what Hamas did
in Israel on Saturday
Israel should try to locate a music festival
in Gaza, for instance
and good luck with that...
should try to find a music festival in Gaza
and rape precisely the number of women
that Hamas raped on Saturday
kill precisely the number of young people
that Hamas killed on Saturday
they should find a town of exactly the same
size
as a town like Sderot
where I've been many times myself
and make sure they go door to door and kill
precisely the correct number
of babies that Hamas killed in Sderot on Saturday
and shoot in the head precisely the same number
of old-age pensioners
as were shot in Sderot on Saturday
just to choose one town
Proportionality in conflict is a joke
and it's a very strange British concept which
we've had
that only the Israeli's in the conflict, when
they are attacked
are expected to have precisely the proportionate
response